<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.t0nd3.AldurAppraiser</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>Aldur Appraiser</name>
  <summary>Passive read-only reward-value overlay for Path of Exile 2</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Aldur Appraiser is a passive, read-only overlay for Path of Exile 2. It
      reads the Runeshape Combinations panel of the Ezomyte Remnant, prices each
      reward option from poe2scout, and shows the value inline next to every
      choice so you can pick the best one at a glance.
    </p>
    <p>Highlights:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Inline value chips at each option, with the best choice highlighted.</li>
      <li>Excludes the always-paid bonus reward from the ranking and marks rewards it cannot price as unknown rather than guessing.</li>
      <li>Read-only by design: screen capture and OCR only, via the desktop screen-cast portal. No clipboard, input injection, or memory access.</li>
      <li>Runs quietly in the system tray.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Use at your own risk: it only reads the screen and draws its own overlay,
      and is not endorsed by Grinding Gear Games.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.t0nd3.AldurAppraiser.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/T0nd3/aldur-appraiser</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/T0nd3/aldur-appraiser/issues</url>

  <developer id="io.github.t0nd3">
    <name>Benjamin</name>
  </developer>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.3.2" date="2026-06-29">
      <description>
        <p>Adds a tray "Auto mode" that continuously appraises the reward panel without pressing the hotkey, lets you bind any key as the hotkey (including a single key like 0) by just pressing it, and keeps one screen-capture session open while the checker runs so Wayland only asks for screen-share permission once instead of on every check.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.1" date="2026-06-28">
      <description>
        <p>Windows fixes: the Temple Planner now opens from the tray menu (the packaged app launched itself the wrong way), and a hotkey that can't be registered — e.g. because the combination is already taken — now warns you instead of failing silently.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-06-28">
      <description>
        <p>Adds the Vaal Temple planner: read the drawn room cards and held medallions off the screen, then get colour-coded best-placement suggestions on a 9×9 grid that respect the in-game adjacency, tier, generator and destabilisation rules. The app now starts to the system tray, where you can launch the price-checker and the temple planner independently and set your own global appraise hotkey.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.4" date="2026-06-19">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes detection of long reward lists: scrolling the panel no longer makes the overlay lose the panel and stop showing values.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.3" date="2026-06-16">
      <description>
        <p>More accurate pricing: an untracked or mis-read reward name no longer matches an unrelated currency that merely shares a word like "Rune" or "Orb" — it now stays unknown instead of showing a wrong price. Adds the Linux Flatpak build.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.2" date="2026-06-16">
      <description>
        <p>Unique-item rewards are now always shown as unknown, the reward ROI captures long option lists, and the inline overlay uses a compact surface to avoid compositor artifacts on other monitors.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
